Guide to the Tenneco Energy History Records
University of Houston Libraries
Tenneco Energy History Records
1946-2014
1974-1988
07/2016-005
Tenneco; Cheatham, Gary; Foster, Joe B.
16.00 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Records in this collection of Tenneco history include three major areas of interest. One group consists of management and planning records created by executives of Tenneco. The second group reflects a joint effort to write the history of Tenneco, Built from Scratch. Draft manuscripts, publication costs, and a Tenneco management reunion reflect the concerted effort to document the company’s history. A third group contains in-house publications reflecting Tenneco’s business accomplishments and publications from a variety of sources that constitute energy industry profiles. A small group of ephemera includes a vinyl record album, photographs, and maps.
Historical Note:
Tennessee Gas (later Tenneco) and its Tennessee pipeline were elements of one of the largest diversified companies in the world. Wade Thompson founded Tenneco Gas shortly after the discovery of natural gas in 1933 in Macon County, Tennessee. In 1943 Henry Gardiner Symonds became the first president of the newly established Tennessee Gas Transmission Company (renamed Tenneco in 1966) in Houston.
A significant aspect of this collection of Tenneco records is the management and planning documents, notes, and speeches accumulated by Joe B. Foster, who held positions with Tenneco for thirty-one years. Among his roles with Tenneco, Foster served as chairman of Tenneco Oil Company, executive vice president of Tenneco Inc., and chairman of Tenneco Gas Pipeline Group. Foster left Tenneco in 1988
Foster graduated from Texas A&M University in 1957 with a B.S. in petroleum engineering and B.B.A. in business administration; he joined Tenneco as a junior petroleum engineer in Oklahoma City the same year. In 1968, Foster became Chief of Planning and Economic Analysis for Tenneco Oil Exploration and Production in Houston and assumed the role of president of Tenneco Oil in 1978. When the Tenneco board divested Tenneco Oil in 1988, Foster retired and founded the Newfield Exploration Company, serving as its chief executive officer until 2000.
Foster’s personal notes, speeches, presentations, and his contributions to the development of a history of Tenneco reveal his keen interest in planning and his personal ruminations on the processes of management. His speech development notes and collected sources and the subsequent speeches Foster delivered to Tenneco management groups, professional conferences, and non-profit gatherings offer insight into multiple responsibilities of leadership.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence; Photographs; Plans; Publications (document genre); Reports; Speeches (documents)
Topical Term:
Business planning; Energy consumption -- United States; Energy policy -- United States; Natural resources -- United States; Petroleum industry and trade -- United States; Petroleum products -- United States; Petroleum reserves -- United States
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Scope and Contents
Records in this collection of Tenneco history include three major areas of interest. One group consists of management and planning records created by executives of Tenneco. The second group reflects a joint effort to write the history of Tenneco, Built from Scratch. Draft manuscripts, publication costs, and a Tenneco management reunion reflect the concerted effort to document the company’s history. A third group contains in-house publications reflecting Tenneco’s business accomplishments and publications from a variety of sources that constitute energy industry profiles. A small group of ephemera includes a vinyl record album, photographs, and maps.
Detailed List of Contents
- Joe B. Foster Correspondence
  - 1977-1986, 1989-2014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Financial Reports
  - Full Cost / Successful Efforts Accounting, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Growth Capital Partners Newsletter, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Quarterly International Summary – Economic and Financial Intelligence, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Tenneco Conversion to Successful Efforts Accounting, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Tenneco Eastern Gulf Division – Eastside & East of Delta Economic Project Area, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Tenneco Economic Analysis Guidelines, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Tenneco Economic and Financial Analysis, 1973-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Tenneco Exploration & Production – Domestic Exploration Economics Study, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Tenneco Financial & Operating Status Reports, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Tenneco Financial Communications Plan; Adams & Rinehart, Inc, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- History Project (Tenneco)
  - Beyond Gas Transmission: the Development of Tenneco Oil, 1945-1967 (David Raley), undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Book and Reunion Financials, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Built From Scratch - Draft Manuscript, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Built From Scratch - Draft Manuscript, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Chronology and Critiques, 2007-2013 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - David Raley Report 1987 Information Book, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    (See Box 13, Folder 15 for related CD)
  - Gardiner Symonds and Tenneco, 2008-2010 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - History of Tenneco Oil Exploration & Production – Draft Manuscript, 2012-2013 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Interview Notes, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Joe B. Foster’s Contribution to the Book, 1988, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Tenneco History Journal - Joe B. Foster, 2011-2013 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Tenneco Oil Exploration & Production Reunion, 1991, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Tenneco Oil Exploration & Production - Draft Manuscript, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Tenneco, Inc. - The Rise (1938-1971) & Fall (1972-1998) - Draft Manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Tennessee Gas and Transmission’s Wartime Pipeline, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Industry Profiles
  In addition to materials described in this series, oversize Industry Profiles are available in Series 11.
  - An Analysis Of The Feasibility Of Separating Exploration From Production Of Oil And Gas On The Outer Continental Shelf, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Baker Hughes Incorporated Annual Report, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - E & P Company Overviews (AGIP - Kerr McGee), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Energy Security - A Report To The President Of The United States, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1988 Oil and Gas Price Outlook, 1986 Revisited? (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Enron Corp. Annual Report, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Energy Policy - American Petroleum Institute, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Energy Policy - Federal, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Energy Policy - Media Coverage & Corporate Analysis, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Gas Research Institute Digest (GRID), 1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Houston Association of Landmen Summit Club-Houston, Texas, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Oil & Petroleum Yearbook, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Petroleum in the Marine Environment, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Phillips - The First 66 Years, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Risk, Uncertainty, and Divergence of Opinion, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - The Best of Breeze: Burlington Resources, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - The Nation’s Energy Future, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - The Offshore Imperative - Shell Oil’s Search for Petroleum in Postwar America (Tyler Priest), 2007 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Oil Industry USA, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - National Petroleum Council
    - Guide to National Petroleum Council Report on United States Energy Outlook, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - National Petroleum Council - Natural Gas - Meeting the Challenges of the Nation’s Growing Natural Gas Demand, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - National Petroleum Council - News Releases, Exploration Operations, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - National Petroleum Council - Ocean Petroleum Resources, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - National Petroleum Council - Offshore Exploration & Production Task Group, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - National Petroleum Council - Report on Law of the Sea Conference, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - National Petroleum Council - The Effect of Regulation, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Petroleum Resources Under The Ocean Floor, 1969, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Tenneco Planning / Policy
  - 1984 As We See It Now (2 copies) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Achieving Success in an Open Environment, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Europe: Monroe, Belgium, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors and Senior Officers Meeting: Energy in Tenneco - Hot Springs, Virginia, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Marketing Response to FERC Order 436 - Opening Interstate Pipeline, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Tenneco Corporate Planning, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Tenneco Corporate Planning Position - Construction, Planning, & Design (CP&D) Slot, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Tenneco Corporate Strategic Plan, 1979-1983 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Tenneco Corporate Strategic Plan Instructions, 1979, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Tenneco Europe Inc. - Planning Process, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Tenneco Gas Pipeline (TGPL) Management Meeting, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Tenneco Inc. 18th Management Meeting, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Tenneco Inc. 19th Management Meeting, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Tenneco Inc. 20th Management Meeting, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Tenneco Inc. 21st Management Meeting (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Tenneco Inc. 22nd Management Meeting, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Tenneco Inc. Management Development, 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Tenneco Long Range Planning, 1974-1981 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Tenneco Summary of Corporate Strategic Plan 1987-1991, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Tenneco Summary of Corporate Strategic Plan 1988-1992, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Tenneco: Administrative Credo, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Tenneco: Directory of Company Locations, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Tenneco: Energy Policy Presentation, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Texas A&M University - College of Engineering Leadership Retreat, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Tenneco Planning and Policy – Joe B. Foster
    - Administrative Goals, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Appointment Book, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Energy Panel Management Meeting: “Energy: Vignettes of Leadership”, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Executive Resource Review, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Personal Reflections, 1970-1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Planning Analysis, 1963-1991 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Red Hill Development vs. Tenneco Inc. - Trial Testimony of Joe B. Foster, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Speech Background and Development, 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Speech Background and Development, 1975-1980 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Speech Background and Development (Publications), 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Energy Options for America - Growth vs. Stagnation, Mobil, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 19, Item 1)
      - The Tax Burden On the Domestic Oil and Gas Industry 1967-1970, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 19, Item 2)
      - Who Owns Big Oil, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 19, Item 3)
      - No Time to Confuse - A Critique of the Final Report of the Energy Policy Project of the Ford Foundation: A Time To Choose America’s Energy Future, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 19, Item 4)
    - Speech Background and Development (Publications), 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Louisiana Oil and Gas Facts – Mid-Continent Oil & Gas Association, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 1)
      - Mississippi & Alabama Oil and Gas Facts – Mid-Continent Oil & Gas Association, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 2)
      - Oil Company Profitability – Committee On Finance United States Senate, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 3)
      - Price Controls and the Natural Gas Shortage – National Energy Project, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 4)
      - The Assault On Private Enterprise, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 5)
      - The Natural Gas Shortage and The Congress – National Energy Project, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 6)
      - Exxon Company, U.S.A.’s Energy Outlook 1975-1990 (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 7)
    - Speech Background and Development (Publications), 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - The Profit Situation – A Special Petroleum Report, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 2, Item 1)
      - Outlook for Natural Gas Supply – The Impact of Shortages on Suppliers and Users, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2, Item 2)
      - The Crisis in Natural Gas – A Congressional Colloquy, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2, Item 3)
      - The Offshore Imperative – The Need For ad Potential Of Offshore Exploration, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2, Item 4)
      - Government Interest In Downstream Operations, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 2, Item 5)
      - Resources – Muddling Through, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 2, Item 6)
      - Exxon USA, First Quarter 1974 (Box 6, Folder 2, Item 7)
    - Speeches - Hysteresis and Hypertension in the Natural Gas Business, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Speeches - People of Vision, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Speeches - River Oaks Breakfast Association (ROBA), 2008 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Speeches - Tenneco Capabilities as an Exploration & Production Company, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Speeches - Various Occasions, 1981-2013 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Tenneco Inc. Issues and Remedies - Notes, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Press Coverage
  - Tenneco & Energy Growth Articles, 1973-2012 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - U.S. Energy and Economy Shortages, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Reorganizations / Sell-Offs (Tenneco)
  - Anaconda Proposed Merger, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Change In Control (CIC) - Benefits Protection Program, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Leveraged Buyout (LBO) Bidding Entity: Encore Oil & Gas, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Leveraged Buyout (LBO) Participant & State Income Statements, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Pemex - Establishing A Cooperative Agreement, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Personnel and Organization Changes, 1974-1981 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Corporate Reorganization & Planning - News Briefs, 1962-2013 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Tenneco - “Offer for Sale”, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Tenneco Gas Pipeline Business Unit, 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Tenneco Eastern Gulf Division OCS Lease Sale 98, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Tenneco Gas Transportation and Tennessee Gas Company Marketing Program, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Tenneco Inc. Acquisition Certificate - La-Terre Co., Inc., 1974 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Tenneco Oil - Exploration & Production Sale Process, L. Wayne Nance Memos, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Tenneco Restructuring Opportunities, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Tenneco - Reorganization of Pipeline Division, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Reports / Contracts
  - “The General Outlook for Petroleum Fuels”, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Air Products and Chemical Settlement Agreement, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Canadian Natural Gas Market, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Comments on Department of Energy (DOE) Gas Decontrol Proposal, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Contract Pricing Language, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Estimate of Ultimate and Available Reserves Offshore Louisiana, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Excerpts from Architecture by Team: A New Concept for the Practice of Architecture, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Exploration & Production Review of Operating Results, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Industry Competitive Position Study for International Exploration & Production Activities, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - International Energy Contracts - Energy Statistics, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Method of Evaluating Undrilled Prospects in the Gulf of Mexico, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 18-19)
  - Pacific Coast Division Field Evaluation, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Petroleum Industry Research Associates, Inc. (PIRA) Energy Briefing, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Property Status Report - Western Gulf Division, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Risk Sharing in the Natural Gas Industry, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Tenneco Oil Exploration & Production Economic Study, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Tenneco Oil Exploration & Production International Competitor Study, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Tenneco Oil Exploration & Production Overview, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Tenneco Oil Processing and Marketing Gasoline Retail, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Tenneco Record of Progress, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Tenneco - Chalmette Refinery Modernization Request, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Tennessee Gas Transmission - Energy Prices & Policy, 1976-1981 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Twentieth Century Petroleum Statistics, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Well Activity - Gulf Coast Division, Rocky Mountain Division, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Tenneco Publications
  In addition to materials described in this series, oversize Tenneco publications are available in Series 11.
  - Tenneco - Service Awards Dinner, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Petroleum Outlook, Jan-Dec, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Petroleum Outlook, Jun, Aug, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Petroleum Outlook, Dec 1985 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Petroleum Outlook, Feb, Apr-May, Jul-Aug, Oct, Dec, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Petroleum Outlook, Jan-Sept, Nov, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Prolog E&P Newsletter, May, Sept, Dec, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Prolog E&P Newsletter, Jun, Nov, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Prolog - Tenneco Oil E&P 1981 Review, 1982 Preview (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Prolog - Tenneco Oil E&P, Jan, Aug, Oct, Dec, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Prolog - Tenneco Oil E&P, Spring, Summer, Fall, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Prolog - Tenneco Oil E&P, Spring, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Tenneco Offshore Company, Inc.: Annual Report, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Tenneco Oil Newsletter, Oct 1976, Apr 1977, Jul 1977 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Tenneco - A Publication of Tenneco Inc., Fall, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Tenneco - A Publication of Tenneco Inc., Winter, Summer, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Tenneco - A Publication of Tenneco Inc., Summer, Fall, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Tenneco - A Publication of Tenneco Inc., Summer, Fall, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Tenneco - A Publication of Tenneco Inc., Fall, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Tenneco - A Publication of Tenneco Inc., Winter-Fall, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Tenneco - A Publication of Tenneco Inc., Winter-Fall, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Tenneco - A Publication of Tenneco Inc., Winter-Fall, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Tenneco - An Oil Industry Study, 1981-1983, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Tenneco; Vol 1-3, 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Tenneco; Vol 4-6, 1970-1972 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Tenneco; Vol 7-9, 1973-1975 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Tenneco; Vol 10-12, 1976-1978 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Tenneco; Vol 13-15 (1 of 2), 1979-1981 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Tenneco; Vol 13-15 (2 of 2), 1979-1981 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Tenneco; Vol 16-18, 1982-1984 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - The Line; Annual Reports, 1956-1957,1959-1967, 1969-1975 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - The Line; Annual Reports, 1976-1987 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - The Line; Annual Reports, 1988-1998 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - The Line, 1967-1970 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - The Line, 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - The Line, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - The Line, 1977-1979 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The Line, 1980-1982 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - The Line, 1983-1986 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - The Line; Vol 1, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - The Line; Vol 2, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - The Line; Vol 3, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - The Line; Vol 4, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - The Line; Vol 5, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - The Line; Vol 6, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - The Line; Vol 7, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - The Line; Vol 8, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - The Line; Vol 9, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - The Line; Vol 10, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - The Line; Vol 11, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - The Line; Vol 12, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - The Line; Vol 13, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - The Line; Vol 14, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - The Line; Vol 15, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - The Line; Vol 16, Jan-Jun, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - The Line; Vol 20, Vol 21, 1965, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Tenneco and Japan, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Tenneco Gas: 50 Years, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Tennessee Gas Transmission: Tradition and Tomorrow, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Tenneco Oil Exploration & Production: Geo - Petrol, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Tenneco Oil Exploration & Production Group - Information Book, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - The Tenneco Model in Norway, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - The T-World: Tennessee Gas Transmission Company, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Topics - Published for Tenneco Houston-Based Employees: Houston-Tenneco Marathon, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - ViewPoint - The News and Views of Tenneco Gas Pipeline Group: Oil Company Sells for $7.3 Billion, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Visions of An Elite Company, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Audio / Visual Media
  - David Raley Report 1987 Information Book CD, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    (text document in Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Speech to Arthur Anderson Seminar “Successful Efforts Accounting” VHS, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Photographs B. Nixon, Tenneco - Photos / Film Aviation 2-CDs, 2012 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Photographs, 1960-2004 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Photographs, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Photographs, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Photographs Executive Head Shots of Tenneco Exploration & Production, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Photographs Exploration & Production Presentation, 1984-1988 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Photographs Tenneco Executives Black & White, 1973-1987 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Photographs Tenneco Executives Color Snapshots, 1973-1987 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Photographs Joe Foster, 1973-1987 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Photographs Offshore Oil Rigs, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Photographs West Cameron 165, Well #3, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
- Oversized
  - Audio / Visual Media
    - No Trespassing Tenneco Oil Co. Houma La., undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Sing With Tenneco Vinyl Record, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Season’s Greetings, Tenneco Oil Exploration & Production Employee List, 1985, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Department of the Interior - Safety Award For Excellence, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Industry Profiles
    - Conoco: 125 Years of Energy, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Exploration Montage: Strata-Cooper Prospect - Liberty County, 2007 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Schlumberger Alta Mesa Services, LP & Mechanical Properties Log, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Maps / Charts
    - Pump Intake Pressure (PIP) Summary - Integrated Hole & Cement Volume Major & Minor, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Tennessee Gas Pipeline - Pipeline District Map, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company - Map of South Louisiana And Offshore Areas - Natural Gas Pipelines, 1976, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company - Map of South Louisiana And Outer Continental Shelf - Natural Gas Pipelines, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company - Map of South Texas and Outer Continental Shelf - Natural Gas Pipelines, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company - Map of West Texas-Natural Gas Pipelines, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Topographical Map - East Texas, undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Tenneco Publications
    - The Line; Vol 16-19, Jul-Dec, 1961-1964 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - E&P Update, Oct-Dec, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - E&P Update, Jan-Dec, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - E&P Update, Jan, Mar-Dec, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - E&P Update, Jan-Feb, May, Jul-Dec, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - E&P Update; The Best Shots, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - E&P Update, Jan-May, Jul-Nov, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 6)